A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Office Files of Alison R. Bernstein FA573
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Executive Officer Subject Files, 1975-2010; 22.38 Cubic Feet 58 containers
  - Ford Foundation Report on Access and Affordability, Nick Ehrmann, 2006-2007 (Box 57, Folder 464)
    A Crisis of Convergence: Increasing Access and Affordability in American Higher Education, A Ford Foundation Workshop, Institute for Higher Education Policy
  - Evaluation of the Ford Foundation's Sexuality Research Fellowship Program, Draft 2, 2003 October 30 (Box 57, Folder 465, Box 58, Folder 466)
  - Meetings and Correspondence, 2008 (Box 58, Folder 467)
    German Round Table Voices for the Res Publica
    Aspen Institute - Congressional Program, The New Role of Higher Education Attainment in Global Competetiveness and Income Opportunity
    Institute of International Education - Scholar Rescue Fund Correspondence
  - Bill and Melinda Gates Foundation Global Libraries Initiative Convening, 2007-2008 (Box 58, Folder 468)
  - Difficult Dialogues, University of Alaska Anchorage - Books of the Year Program, 2008 (Box 58, Folder 469)
    Theme: Alaska's Native Peoples: A Call to Understanding
  - From Tragedy to Unity: A Celebration of the Human Spirit, A Multidisciplinary Symposium Commemorating the Anniversary of September 11, Virtue Foundation, 2002-2003 (Box 58, Folder 470)
  - University of Pennsylvania 10th Anniversary Conference, Center for Community Partnerships, 2003 (Box 58, Folder 471)
  - National Urban Fellows, 2004-2008 (Box 58, Folder 472)
  - Knowledge, Creativity, and Freedom Program, New York Staff Retreat, El Museo del Barrio, Teatro Heckscher, 2006 (Box 59, Folder 473)
  - Knowledge, Creativity, and Freedom Program Briefing Book, Johannesburg/Magaliesburg, South Africa, 2005 November (Box 59, Folder 474)
  - Matthew Connelly Lunch - Fatal Misconception: The Struggle to Control World Population, 2008 (Box 59, Folder 475)
  - Gilberto Gil, Minister of Culture of Brazil, Intellectual Property Address, Board Meeting Luncheon, 2007 (Box 59, Folder 476)
  - Geena Davis Luncheon, 2006 (Box 59, Folder 477)
  - Charles Rangel Center for Public Service, CCNY, 2005 (Box 59, Folder 478)
  - Knowledge, Creativity, and Freedom Program, New York Staff Retreat, National Museum of the American Indian, New York City, 2007 September 26 (Box 59, Folder 479)
  - Henry Becton, WGBH Correspondence, 2006 (Box 59, Folder 480)
  - Knowledge, Creativity, and Freedom Reflection Memos, Worldwide Meeting, Johannesburg, South Africa, 2005 November (Box 59, Folder 481)
  - Knowledge, Creativity, and Freedom Program, All Staff Reflections, 2006 October (Box 60, Folder 482)
  - Knowledge, Creativity, and Freedom Program Briefing Book, Worldwide Meeting, Beijing/Guilin, 2006 October 8-13 (Box 60, Folder 483)
  - Kate Whitney - Dr. Sally and Bennett Shaywitz Lunch - Understanding and Treating Dyslexia, 2007 February (Box 60, Folder 484)
  - From Tragedy to Unity: A Celebration of the Human Spirit, A Multidisciplinary Symposium Commemorating the Anniversary of September 11, Virtue Foundation, 2002-2003 (Box 60, Folder 485)
  - Vice Presidents/Deputy Vice Presidents Retreat, 2003 November (Box 60, Folder 486)
  - World Social Forum, 2003 December (Box 60, Folder 487)
  - Vector III Committee Reports and Documents, 2004-2007 (Box 60, Folder 488-489)
  - Vassar College - Correspondence, 2006 (Box 60, Folder 490)
  - University of the Witwatersrand, 2003-2004 (Box 61, Folder 491)
  - Roberta Uno's Program Officer Memo (POM), 2005 (Box 61, Folder 492)
  - Exploring Transfer Program 20th Anniversary Celebration, Vassar College, 2004 (Box 61, Folder 493)
  - Transitioning Program Staff Guidelines, 2006 (Box 61, Folder 494)
  - U.S. Department of the Treasury Anti-Terrorist Financing Guidelines, 2005 (Box 61, Folder 495)
  - Teacher Education Initiatives - New Education Program Officer Email Exchange, 2006 (Box 61, Folder 496)
  - Presidents List: Universities/Colleges, 2004 July (Box 61, Folder 497)
  - Swarthmore College - Alison Bernstein Visit - Itinerary and Correspondence, 2004 (Box 61, Folder 498)
  - James Symington, American Russian Cultural Cooperation Foundation Correspondence, 2003 (Box 61, Folder 499)
  - Sustainable Spaces Convening, 2005 May-June (Box 61, Folder 500)
  - CSA, Center of Contemporary Architecture, with the support of the Ford Foundation, undated; DVD (Box 61, Folder 500)
  - Ford Foundation and Centr Sovremennoj Architectury presents The House of the State Industry Gosprom, Sergey Serafimov, Samuil Kravets, and Mark Felger, Irina Korobjina, 2005 (Box 61, Folder 500)
  - Sexuality and Sexual Health File, 2002-2006 (Box 61, Folder 501)
  - Ford/Rockefeller Video Conference - Camille Billops, 2003 (Box 61, Folder 502)
  - Ford Reserve Claims, 2001-2007 (Box 61, Folder 503-515)
  - Replenishing Democracy Project, 2003-2004 (Box 62, Folder 516)
  - New Orleans South Africa Connection Jazz Festival - Regrets Sent, 2003 (Box 62, Folder 517)
  - Reflection Memos on International Fellowships Program and Affirmative Action, 2003 (Box 62, Folder 518)
  - Robert Redford Remarks, Nancy Hanks Lecture on Arts and Public Policy, 2003 September (Box 62, Folder 519)
  - Education, Media, Arts, and Culture (EMAC) Reflection Retreat, 2000 September (Box 62, Folder 520)
  - Knowledge, Creativity & Freedom Program, New York Staff Retreat 2005, University Inn and Conference Center at Rutgers University, 2005 September 12-13 (Box 62, Folder 521)
  - Alison Bernstein's Beijing, China Visit (including He Jin's Reflection Memo), 2005 October 10-18 (Box 62, Folder 522)
  - Ford Foundation Freedom of Expression and Democratization of Media Cross-Program Global Meeting, 2003-2004 (Box 62, Folder 523)
  - Knowledge, Creativity, and Freedom All New York Staff Retreat, Arden House, Harriman, New York, 2004 September (Box 62, Folder 524)
  - Knowledge, Creativity and Freedom Program Briefing Book - Johannesburg/Magaliesburg, South Africa, 2004 November 15-20 (Box 63, Folder 525-526)
  - Ford Foundation Arts Education Initiative Grantee Convening, 2005 May 2-3 (Box 63, Folder 527)
  - Knowledge, Creativity and Freedom Program Retreat 2003, Harrison Conference Center, 2003 September 30-October 1 (Box 63, Folder 528)
  - Ford Foundation Cross Programme Meeting, Freedom of Expression and Democratisation of the Media, Steve Buckley, President, World Association of Community Radio Broadcasters (AMARC), 2004 February-March (Box 64, Folder 529)
  - The Special Initiative for Africa Citizenship and Identity Workshop, Hilton Hotel, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia, 2003 June 9-12 (Box 64, Folder 530)
  - The Ford Foundation Innovative Women Leaders of Religious Communities Consultation, Religion, Society, and Culture (Education, Media, Arts, and Culture (EMAC)), 2002 May 13-14 (Box 64, Folder 531)
  - Program Leadership Meeting - Review of the Ford Foundation Social Sciences Program: Strengthening and Diversifying the Social Sciences Initiative, 2001 March (Box 64, Folder 532)
  - Alison Bernstein's Visit to Cuzco and Lima, Peru, Education Reform Program, 2005 April 22-28 (Box 64, Folder 533)
    Includes agenda, travel info, and Marita Palacios' reflections from 2004
  - Alison Bernstein, Margaret Wilkinson Preparatory Visit for Knowledge, Creativity, and Freedom Trustee Visit, Cairo, 2006 January 27-31 (Box 64, Folder 534)
  - All Africa Meeting 2007, Cairo Higher Education Program Grantee Visit, 2007 September (Box 64, Folder 535)
  - Education and Scholarship Learning Group, Washington, D.C. and New York City, 2007 October 21-26 (Box 65, Folder 536)
  - Visit to Chile, Alison Bernstein, Briefing Book, 2007 November 19-20 (Box 65, Folder 537)
  - Ford Foundation 2008 Biennial Worldwide Program Meeting, Lines of Work Program Statements Section C (Box 65, Folder 538)
  - Ford Foundation 2008 Biennial Worldwide Program Meeting, Regional Office Program Statements (Box 65, Folder 539)
  - New York Staff Retreat, Alvin Ailey American Dance Theater, New York, 2008 September 17 (Box 65, Folder 540)
  - Alison Bernstein, Cairo Visit, 2009 October 30-November 5 (Box 66, Folder 541)
  - Discussion Paper: Diversity in American Higher Education, For Discussion at the June 1992 Meeting of the Education and Culture Committee (Box 66, Folder 542)
  - 1996 Ford Foundation Campus Diversity Initiative Conference (Box 66, Folder 543)
  - Excellence Through Diversity: Profiles of Forty-two Ford Foundation Fellows, National Research Council, 1996 (Box 66, Folder 544)
  - Education, Media, Arts and Culture Annual Program Review Meeting, Garden City, New York, 1997 September 3-4 (Box 66, Folder 545)
  - Worldwide Meeting on Religion, Cairo, Egypt, 1997 January 20-22 (Box 66, Folder 546)
  - Biennial Representatives and Directors Meeting, 1997 February 24-28 (Box 66, Folder 547)
  - Education, Media, Arts and Culture (EMAC) Trustees Meeting, Miami, Florida, 1997 March 25-27 (Box 67, Folder 548)
  - Worldwide Workshop for Media, Arts and Culture Programmers, Jakarta and Yogyakarta, Indonesia, 1998 April 15-21 (Box 67, Folder 549)
  - Education, Media, Arts and Culture Annual New York Programming Review Meeting, Tarrytown, New York, 1998 September 9-10 (Box 67, Folder 550)
  - Transfer Education in American Community Colleges, Submitted by: Center for the Study of Community Colleges, Submitted to: The Ford Foundation, 1985 April 9 (Box 67, Folder 551)
  - World Meeting on Education and Culture, Bali, Indonesia, 1985 May 13-17 (Box 68, Folder 552)
  - Ten Years Later: The Ford Foundation Upper Division Scholars: A Report to the Office of the Education and Culture, The Ford Foundation, Submitted by The School Services Division Academy for Educational Development, 1987 April (Box 68, Folder 553)
    Grant #850-0424
  - Draft - Status of Ford Foundation Postdoctoral Fellowship Recipients from the Ford Foundation Postdoctoral Fellowships for Minorities Program (1980-1993) prepared by the National Research Council, 1996 June (Box 68, Folder 554)
  - An Assessment of Urban Community Colleges Transfer Opportunities Program, The Ford Foundation's Second Stage Transfer Opportunity Awards, Grant 850-0425, Final Report, Submitted to the Ford Foundation by the Center for the Study of Community Colleges, 1988 April 30 (Box 68, Folder 555)
  - Building Human Capital: The Impact of Post-Secondary Education on AFDC Recipients in Five States, A Report to the Ford Foundation, 1993 March (Box 68, Folder 556)
    Marilyn Gittell, Director with Jill Gross and Jennifer Holdaway, Howard Samuels State Management and Policy Center City University of New York Graduate Center
  - Briefing Book on Visit to Project GRAD in Houston, 2000 March 1-3 (Box 68, Folder 557)
  - Visit by the President, Trustees and Spouses or Guests, and Education, Media, Arts and Culture Leadership to the Moscow Office of the Ford Foundation, 2001 April 22-27 (Box 68, Folder 558)
  - Arts and Culture: From Heritage to Folklore, The Ford Foundation 1952-2002, Celebrating 50 Years of Partnership (Box 68, Folder 559)
  - Knowledge, Creativity and Freedom Program - Program Officer Memos, 2002-2006 (Box 68, Folder 560, Box 69, Folder 561)
    Includes field analysis, course of action, initiative outlines, grant lists for the following program officers:
    Box: 68, Folder: 560
    Elizabeth Theobald Richards
    Robert Uno
    Maria Amelua Palacios
    Jorge Balan
    Charles Bailey
    Box: 69, Folder: 561
    Constance H. Buchanan
    Robert Burnet
    Sarah H. Costa
    Cyrus Driver
    Jon Funabiki
    Irina Iurna
    He Jin
    Ondina Fachel Leal
    Becky Lentz
    Lisa J. Messersmith
    Janice Petrovich
    Margaret B. Wilkerson
    Philip Yampolsky
  - Knowledge, Creativity and Freedom Program Handbook, 2008 June (Box 69, Folder 562-563)
    Arts and Culture
    Media
    Religion, Society and Culture
    Education and Scholarship
    KCF1 - Arts and Culture - Support for Arts
    KCF2 - Arts and Culture - Historical Memory/Museums
    KCF3 - Arts and Culture - Artistic Freedom and Expression
    KCF4 - Media - Public Media and Journalism
    KCF5 - Media - Media Content
    KCF6 - Media - Media Access
    KCF7 - Religion, Society and Culture - Religion and Social Justice
    KCF8 - Religion, Society and Culture - Understanding Religion
    KCF9 - Education and Scholarship - Urban Public Education
    KCF10 - Education and Scholarship - Education for Rural, Indigenous, and Ethnic Peoples
    KCF11 - Education and Scholarship - Higher Education Access
    KCF12 - Education and Scholarship - Building Fields of Knowledge
  - Profiles of National and Community Service in 18 Countries - Papers Prepared for Ford Foundation's Worldwide Workshop on Youth Involvement as a Strategy for Social, Economic, and Democratic Development, San Jose, Costa Rica, 2000 January 4-7 (Box 70, Folder 564-565)
  - Education, Media, Arts, and Culture (EMAC) Worldwide Meeting, 2000 December 4-8 (Box 70, Folder 566)
  - Joint Worldwide Meeting, 2002 October 27-November 1 (Box 70, Folder 567-568)
  - Ford Foundation Fiscal Year 2002, Grant-Making Review, Office of Management Services, 2003 February (Box 71, Folder 569)
  - Ford Foundation Glossary of Pools (From Fiscal Year 2003 Grant Budgets) (Box 71, Folder 570)
  - Media, Arts and Culture Learning Circle Meeting, Accra, Ghana, 2004 February 9-13 (Box 71, Folder 571)
  - A Convening on GLBT Rights and Issues in the US: Framing Difficult Dialogues and Seeking New Partnerships, Ford Foundation, 2004 April 12-13 (Box 71, Folder 572)
  - Knowledge, Creativity and Freedom Program, Trustee Committee Visit to Egypt, Background Materials, 2006 March 5-10 (Box 71, Folder 573)
  - Knowledge, Creativity and Freedom Program Briefing Book, Worldwide Meeting, Beijing/Guilin, China, 2006 October 8-13 (Box 71, Folder 574)
  - Media, Arts and Culture Learning Circle Meeting, Moscow, Russia, 2007 September 29-October 5 (Box 71, Folder 575)
  - Report on Anti-Semitism in Europe, 2004 February 24 (Box 72, Folder 576)
  - Campus Diversity Public Information Project, 2000 August 25 (Box 72, Folder 577)
  - Public Experience, Attitudes, and Knowledge: A Report on Two National Surveys About International Education, Fred M. Hayward and Laura M. Siaya, 2001 (Box 72, Folder 578)
  - Program Leadership Meeting, 2001 March (Box 72, Folder 579)
  - The Education Pipeline in East Africa: A Research Report and Synthesis of Consultations in Kenya, Tanzania and Uganda, 2001 May (Box 72, Folder 580)
  - A Conception of a Masters on Alternative Development, M.A. Mohamed Salih and Paschal Mihyo, undated (Box 72, Folder 581)
  - A Reflection on and Taking Stock of Innovations at Makerere University, Nakakyike B. Musisi, Presented at the "Innovations in African Higher Education" Workshop, 2001 October 1-3 (Box 72, Folder 582)
  - Gender Equity Programming in Higher Education, Penina Mlama, 2001 September 25 (Box 72, Folder 583)
  - Education Learning Circle, San Juan, Puerto Rico, 2001 July 23-26 (Box 72, Folder 584)
  - Africa Higher Education Partnership, 2001 October 1-3 (Box 72, Folder 585)
  - Education, Media, Arts and Culture (EMAC) Retreat, The Nassau Inn, Princeton, New Jersey, 2001 October 10-11 (Box 72, Folder 586)
  - Program Leadership Meeting, 2003 February 18-21 (Box 73, Folder 587)
  - I'll Meet You Halfway: The Media and the Public, A Progress Report on Efforts to Improve Connections Between Journalists and Their Communities, Convening Sponsored by The Media, Arts, and Culture Unit, 2002 April 22 (Box 73, Folder 588)
  - Education, Media, Arts and Culture (EMAC) Trustee Visit to the American Southwest, 2002 (Box 73, Folder 589)
  - Knowledge, Creativity and Freedom Program Retreat, Harrison Conference Center, 2002 October 7-8 (Box 73, Folder 590)
  - Promoting Public Participation in Education Governance, Program Proposal, HakiElimu, Tanzania, 2001 July-2003 December (Box 73, Folder 591)
  - Kathryn Fuller, Annual Dinner and Women of the Year Awards, 2007 (Box 73, Folder 592)
  - Board Meeting, 2005 January (Box 73, Folder 593)
  - Guidelines for Grant Proposals - Integrating the Arts and Education Reform (ArtsEd), 2005 July 20 (Box 73, Folder 594)
  - Guidelines for Grant Reports, 2005 July 20 (Box 73, Folder 595)
  - Guidelines for Reviewing Ford Foundation Support for Large International Conferences, 2004 (Box 73, Folder 596)
  - USC Annenberg Institute for Justice and Journalism, 2003 (Box 73, Folder 597)
  - Governance and Civil Society - Moving NGO Headquarters from Global North to Global South - Manual and Overview Articles, 2007 (Box 73, Folder 597)
    Created by Nell and Shapiro (South Africa) and INTRAC (U.K.)
  - Global Dialogues for Sexual Health and Wellbeing - Regional Evaluation, 2008 (Box 74, Folder 598)
  - HIV/Sexuality and Reproductive Health Meetings, 2006-2008 (Box 74, Folder 599)
  - Ford Foundation Board Meeting, 2007 May 23 (Box 74, Folder 600)
  - Ford Foundation Trustee Membership, 2006 May 1 (Box 74, Folder 601)
  - Difficult Dialogues, 2007 September 17 (Box 74, Folder 602)
  - Ford Foundation Board Meeting Letters for Signature by Alison R. Bernstein, 2000-2007 (Box 74, Folder 603)
  - Management and Governance Committee Meeting, 2007 September 19 (Box 74, Folder 604)
  - Knowledge Creativity & Freedom Program - Trustee Committee Meeting, 2007 September 19 (Box 74, Folder 605)
  - Communications and Society Program, Democratic Enterprise: Sustaining Media and Civil Society, Craig L. LaMay, 2003 (Box 74, Folder 606)
  - Project Report: South Africa, American Council on Education, International Initiatives, 1996 July (Box 74, Folder 607)
  - Public Airwaves As a Common Asset and Public Good, 2005 March 11 (Box 74, Folder 608)
  - Program Officer Orientation, 2006 January (Box 75, Folder 609)
  - Program Officer Orientation, 2005 January (Box 75, Folder 610)
  - Ford Foundation Policy - Staff Political Activities, 2003 September (Box 75, Folder 611)
  - Program Leadership Meeting, 2004 March (Box 75, Folder 612)
  - Program Officer Memo - Maria Palacios, Knowledge, Creativity and Freedom, Andean Region and the Southern Cone, Equal Access to Knowledge for the Children of the Poor, 2003 (Box 75, Folder 613)
  - Program Leadership Meeting, 2007 February 27-March 2 (Box 75, Folder 614)
  - Program Leadership Retreat, 2005 December 5-6 (Box 75, Folder 615)
  - Program Officer Orientation, 2003 December (Box 75, Folder 616)
  - Pathways to Higher Education Initiative Grants - Rio, Hanoi, and Santiago, 2004 June (Box 75, Folder 617)
  - Photographs, 1995-2005 (Box 75, Folder 618)
    Alison Bernstein headshots, 1996
    Fall 1998 #25 - Njabulo Ndebele/New Scholar
    China Visit, 2005 October
    Education and Culture Program, Worldwise Workshop on Culture, Bamako, Mai and Dakar, Senegal, January 15-20, 1995
  - China Visit, 2005 October; CD (Box 75)
  - Project GRAD, 2002-2004 (Box 75, Folder 619-620)
  - New Performance Appraisal Process, 2004 (Box 75, Folder 621)
  - Palestine/Israel Articles, 2001-2003 (Box 75, Folder 622)
  - Philanthropy Big Bet, Philanthropy Learning Group, 2003-2004 (Box 75, Folder 623)
  - Office of Management Services Retreats, 2001 (Box 75, Folder 624)
  - Ford Foundation New Directions/New Donors for the Arts Fourth Annual Convening, 2003 May 12-13 (Box 75, Folder 625)
  - New Senior Program Officers Appointments, Office of Management Services, 2003 June (Box 76, Folder 626)
  - Office Updates, 2004 January-February (Box 76, Folder 627)
  - New Assignments in Office of Management Services Memo - Salim Sufi and Kyle Reis, 2002 May 29 (Box 76, Folder 628)
  - National Project II: Alternatives to the Revolving Door, Richard A. Donovan, The Fund for the Improvement of Postsecondary Education, 1975 (Box 76, Folder 629)
  - The National Trust for 21st Century Artists: A Prospectus, Prepared for the Ford and Rockefeller Foundations, James Pickman and Susan Kenny Stevens, 2004 March 10 (Box 76, Folder 630)
  - National Council for Research on Women (NCRW) Flyer - A Conversation with Mamphela Ramphele, 2004 March 11 (Box 76, Folder 631)
  - New Directions/New Donors for the Arts Fourth Convening, 2003 May 12-13 (Box 76, Folder 632)
  - Middle East and Africa Program Meeting, 2004 March 6 (Box 76, Folder 633)
  - Minority Fellowships Program, 2000 March 10 (Box 76, Folder 634)
  - Design Services, 2003 (Box 76, Folder 635)
  - Janet Lieberman, The Steinhardt School of Education Distinguished Alumni Award, 2003 January 9 (Box 76, Folder 636)
  - Lincoln Center Luncheon, 2006 (Box 76, Folder 637)
  - Media, Arts, and Culture (MAC) Conversation Series on Media, Technology, Society and Culture - "Information Gathering Technologies vs. Civil Liberties, The Electronic Privacy Information Center (Becky Lentz), 2003 (Box 76, Folder 638)
  - Media and Arts, and Culture Grantmaking: An Historical Profile, 1951-2001, Lynn E. Stern, 2003 August (Box 76, Folder 639)
  - Amherst College: Replenishing Democracy, Summer Institute on Civic Engagement and Political Activism, 2005 June (Box 76, Folder 640)
  - Anthony Marx, Amherst College - Replenishing Democracy Project, 2004 (Box 76, Folder 641)
  - LINC: Leveraging Investments in Creativity Training, 2003 (Box 76, Folder 642)
  - Anti-Terrorism Language for Grant Letters, 2003 (Box 76, Folder 643)
  - Becky Lentz Program Officer Memo File, 2003 (Box 76, Folder 644)
  - Academic Innovation: Individuals, Networks, Patronage: An Evaluation of Academic Community Building in Russia - Draft, Stephen Kotkin, 2006 June (Box 77, Folder 645)
  - KnowledgeWorks Foundation, Chad P. Wick, 2003 (Box 77, Folder 646)
  - Lagos Media, Arts, and Culture (MAC) File - The Treasures Within: Creative Industries: The West African Story So Far, 2004 (Box 77, Folder 647)
  - Ford Foundation International Intellectual Property Initiative (IIPI) Committee - Reflection Memo and Correspondence, 2005-2008 (Box 77, Folder 648)
  - IT Working Files, 2005 (Box 77, Folder 649)
  - Joint Worldwide Meeting - Speakers, 2002 (Box 77, Folder 650)
  - Siddharth Kak, Surabh Foundation for Research and Cultural Exchange, 2004 (Box 77, Folder 651)
  - New Century Scholars - India, 2004 (Box 77, Folder 652)
  - An Initiative to Address Anti-Jewish Bigotry in Europe, Alexander Karp, Jewish Philanthropy Partnership, 2004 (Box 77, Folder 653)
  - Commission on Human Security, undated (Box 77, Folder 654)
  - International Conference on Population and Development (ICPD), London, 2004 August 31-September 3 (Box 77, Folder 655)
  - He Jin's Program Officer Memo (POM), 2003 July (Box 77, Folder 656)
  - Funding for US Colleges (Fiscal Year 2004), 2004 December (Box 77, Folder 657)
  - John Gerhart Obituaries, 2003 July (Box 77, Folder 658)
  - Judith Goldstein, Humanity in Action, 2004 (Box 77, Folder 659)
  - On-Time Grantmaking Task Force - GBS System Updates, 2002-2003 (Box 78, Folder 660)
  - International Coalition of Historic Site Museums of Conscience Conference, 2003 (Box 78, Folder 661)
  - Ford Foundation Policy Letter, 2004 January 8 (Box 78, Folder 662)
  - New Art at the Ford Foundation 10th Floor Gallery, 1998 May (Box 78, Folder 663)
  - Nancy Feller - Affiliated Grants and Executive Order 13224 Guidance, 2003-2004 (Box 78, Folder 664)
  - Ford Foundation Sponsored Fellowship Programs Administered by Other Associations and List of Publications for Financial Aid Sources, 1997 (Box 78, Folder 665)
  - Proposal to the Ford Foundation to Support a Commissioned Work, Tan Dun, The Met Opera, 2003 (Box 78, Folder 666)
  - Memos and Correspondence, 2003 (Box 78, Folder 667)
  - Ford Foundation Leadership for a Changing World Nomination Announcement, 2003 (Box 78, Folder 668)
  - Bill Challenges Ford Foundation, Daniel Howes, The Detroit News, 2006 June (Box 78, Folder 669)